Gianni St. Clair

gstclair19@gmail.com | (321)-525-2442 | Phoenix, AZ github.com/Gstclair1 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/gianni-st-clair/

Adaptive learner with exceptional analytical skills and a background in medicine. Eager to leverage these skills as a junior level developer. In pursuit of an environment to continue to grow and succeed as a programmer.

Technical Skills:

Python | Java | Flask | HTML | CSS | REST API | Spring Boot | PostgreSQL | JavaScript | Vue.js | Responsive Design | IntelliJ | PyCharm | Git | Unit Testing (JUnit) | JSON | Bootstrap | Selenium WebDriver | Beautiful Soup | Tkinter | EPIC Software

Technical Experience:

Fantasy Hockey Application - Produced an object oriented fantasy hockey application with Java and SQL that incorporates a custom API. The application takes user input to store user, roster and team record information and utilizes authentication. Tenmo RESTful API - Constructed an API utilizing Java and SQL in a pair-programming experience with an accompanying command line interface. The API allows for authenticated users to transfer funds and request transfers from other users. Vending Machine Application - Designed an object oriented virtual vending machine using Java and File I/O in a pair-programming experience. The application accepts user input, keeps an inventory of items, and returns change. Coffee Machine - A text-based program made using Python that prompts the user to enter their choice of drink and an amount of change into the machine and it "serves" the drink. The application keeps an inventory of specific finite resources. Cafe Site & API - Built a website using Python and Flask that displays Café information (name, location, etc) and allows cafes to be added. Employs a separately created API to retrieve and update data.

Quiz Application - Created a True/False Quiz application utilizing Python and Tkinter that fetches a unique set of questions for each round using the Open Trivia Database API.

Blog Site - Assembled a blog style website with Python, HTML5 and CSS using Flask and SQLalchemy that displays blog posts and allows for comment. Logged in users can comment and admins can create posts. Login utilizes authentication.

Education

Tech Elevator, National Live Remote

October 2022 - February 2023

Currently attending a 14-week full-stack coding bootcamp learning how to create dynamic web-based software systems using Java providing 700+ hours of development education and application

Udemy: 100 days of code

June - August 2022

Python bootcamp covering automation, game, app, web development, data science, and machine learning Built 100 unique projects

University of Florida College of Medicine

June - October 2020

Took credits towards a Masters of Physician Assistant Studies

University of Florida, Gainesville, Fl

May 2019

Bachelor of Applied Physiology and Kinesiology, Exercise Physiology - Magna Cum Laude

Professional Experience

UF Health Physicians, Gainesville, FL

ENT & Allergy - The Oaks Clinic Children's Medical Services Clinic February 2021 - May 2022 August 2019 - May 2020

Medical Assistant

Intern

- Coordinated patient rooming, vital signs, and medical histories for 35-50 patients daily
- Facilitated procedure preparation and ensured assistance was provided
- Prioritized patient safety at all times by following and expanding upon facility guidelines

Disabled Sports Eastern Sierra, Mammoth Lakes, CA

January - April 2019

- Oversaw skiing and snowboarding lessons for students with a wide range of disabilities
- Evaluated students' skills and developed strong lesson plans to facilitate advancement in skill
- Adapted to each student's disability's unique obstacles to ensure a safe and enjoyable experience